

UTKARSH AREN

Human Resources Professional

A Jombay **HR30underThirty** winner, high performing, passionate, result oriented HR professional with over 5 years of professional experience. Currently Working as Senior Manager - Compensation & Benefits Partner at HDFC Bank Gurgaon since May 2023, post completion of his MBA in HRM from XLRI Jamshedpur in 2019. Has been certified in HR Business Partnering from SHRM. Prior to rewards, worked as Corporate HRBP for a duration of 4years in HDFC Bank from June 2019



arenutkarsh@gmail.com



Gurgaon, Haryana



linkedin.com/in/utkarsh-aren-197b14a3



+91 8800318800

SKILLS

- HR Business Partnering
- Stakeholder Management
- Org Design & Structuring
- **Talent Management**
- **Total Rewards**
- Leadership Hiring
- **Employee Engagement**
- Market Benchmarking
- Manpower Budgeting
- **Succession Planning**
- Performance Management
- **Employee Communication**

PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

KEY TALENT – FY 2023-24 & FY2020-21

Identified as a Key Performer for displaying leadership qualities & excellence in current role

• SILVER STAR – September 2022 For managing end to end work on performance appraisal cycle with all necessary checks & final submission to Comp & Ben team

Jombay HR30UNDERthirty Nominated by HDFC Bank to participate in a cohort of over 1000 HR professionals across all industries. Post 3 months of rigorous multiple assessments, declared the winner of the program

WORK EXPERIENCE

HDFC Bank Pvt Ltd, Gurgaon

Senior Manager- Compensation & Benefits Partner May 2023- Present

- Responsible for salary offers & fitments across all the bands for respective business verticals - IT, Digital Banking, Operations, Information Security group covering over 25.000 employees
- Stakeholder Management: Liaise with all key stakeholders i.e. HRBPs, Talent Acquisition teams, Business managers for deeper understanding of business realities & ensure alignment with the same
- Carried out the job sizing for all business verticals within the portfolio with over 300 unique job roles using the frameworks to ascertain all roles have defined job size
- Anchored the **Annual PMS** involving annual salary review, promotions, salary corrections across the bands for 2 cycles
- Formulated the flexi pay merit increment methodology for IT/ Digital business as a pilot project for the first time in Bank covering over 3,000 employees
- Provisioned for Annual Bonus using multiple approaches for ascertaining the budget required, coordinated with Finance for allocation at the organization level
- Managed the BDP process involving bonus calculation methodology, liaised with business heads for determination of annual business results, & with finance for all the revenue generating businesses involving over 1 lakh employees
- Responsible for salary benchmarking for all job roles at all bands within the organization. Coordinated with multiple external vendors for the same
- Worked on LTI scheme covering ESOPs & RSUs cost calculations, accounting costs & analysis across all FYs grants, carrying out simulations for computation of cost over next 4-5 years
- Conducted compa ratio & talent category analysis project at the organization level to understand placement of each employee in 9 box matrix & proposed recommendations for each box separately

❖ HDFC Bank Pvt Ltd, Mumbai

Senior Manager- Corporate HR Business Partner Dec 2022 – April 2023 Manager- Corporate HR Business Partner *June 2019 – Nov 2022*

- Supported BU **Operations** as central HRBP spanning **pan India** with an employee base of over **15,000** employees located in multiple geographies
- Handled the entire employee life cycle for the senior leadership team with designation from **Senior VP to Group Head** comprising over 90 staff in BU Operations
- Responsible for Manpower planning by assessing the future business needs & monitoring current headcount budgets, attrition, actuals & staff movements with regional/functional heads of business
- Coordinated & liaised with Finance, Regional HRBP, Regional Talent Acquisition teams in order to streamline approval of new headcount budgets, creation of new positions within TAT in the HRMS

- SILVER STAR September 2020 For Intervention towards Org Structure Streamlining exercise for BU Operations
- WOW PERFORMER- August 2019 For developing advanced tools for optimization of Org Design & Spans

EDUCATION

- PGDM –HRM
 XLRI- Xavier School of
 Management, Jamshedpur
 2017-2019
- B.tech Electrical Engg.
 Jamia Millia Islamia University,
 Delhi

2012-2016

- Facilitated Organizational Design, restructuring with BU Heads by providing business insights for optimum decision making leading to 30% increase in ideal SPANs
- Designed & Delivered HR KBO presentations to BU Heads encompassing details on manpower, performance management, job rotation, attrition pockets, employee engagement scores on monthly basis
- Data Management, supporting rating validations, initiating promotion discussions during the Performance Appraisal process
- Facilitate Succession planning with BU heads by identifying critical roles, formulating career paths for the senior leaders (Senior VP & above)
- Streamlined Rewards & Recognition policy, designed new categories for recognition basis the BU needs leading to increase in coverage by 25%

MyPopCoins Loyalty Pvt Ltd, Delhi

Manager- Corporate Sales

July 2016 – March 2017

- Responsible for delivering B2B sales by onboarding potential retailers in food & service, lifestyle, health & wellness industry
- Analyzed market trends, identified prospective clients, prepared the sales pitch & deck, supported sales team for contract closures by leading field visits
- Led a 5 member team, carried out multiple field visits ensuring vendors are on boarded in an optimum manner

ACADAMIC & LIVE PROJECTS

- Assessment Centre (Live Project XLRI Jamshedpur)
- Designed a 7 hour integrated simulation to measure 5 competencies of an Individual
- Delivered detailed analysis, verbal & written feedback to the assesse on the performance
- Training & Development (Live Project XLRI Jamshedpur)
- Carried out Needs Assessment for Crossword Book Store, designing training prog for Sales Executives
- Conducted surveys, interviews to identify KSA gaps, measured expected ROI of training